

JULIAN CAMILO SANCHEZ DIAZ

Birthdate: August 6, 1987 Home Address: Carrera 32A # 25B-75

> T.2 Apt.902 City: Bogotá D.C

Phone number: +57 3164739303 E-mail: <u>juliansan77@gmail.com</u>

ABOUT ME

Software Developer with background experience in various areas such as telecommunication and business companies along with knowledge in programming.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Systems Engineer from Catholic University of Colombia, proactive, teamwork skills, good communication and learning.

Updated and trained daily to give support, maintenance and control over Software systems, Software Engineering processes (Analysis, Design, Implementation and Testing), experience in Object-oriented programming (OOP) languages such as C# and Java with knowledge in PL/SQL on relational databases.

EDUCATION

FORMAL

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF COLOMBIA

Security Information Specialist April 2017

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF COLOMBIA

Systems engineer September 2013

EMILIO VALENZUELA SCHOOL

High School Degree December 2004

INFORMAL

- Fundamentals of The Java Programming Language Java SE 8
- Java Programming Language Java SE 8

Java Basic

Object-oriented programming, Catholic University of Colombia 2010

Sena virtual

- Variables and Control structures in Java Object Oriented Programming
- Development of applications with Graphical Interface, Handling of Events, Classes and Java Objects
- Application Development with Data Management in Java Memory

EXPERIENCE

CAPGEMINI

Expert Lead .Net Developer (2022/11-2023/10) 1 Year 1 Month

Functions and Achievements

Preparation of application design for new solutions in .NET technology, technical analysis of existing systems and designing their expansion with new modules and components.

Supporting the development team as part of the projects as a technical leader.

Technologies:

- C#, .Net, .Net Core, Go, React
- PL/SQL
- HTML, CSS

SCOTIABANK

Software Engineer Specialist (2020/11-2022/07)

1 Year 9 Months

Functions and Achievements

Analytical, problem solving and trouble shooting skills in order to develop and support systems to meet user requirements.

Be creative and flexible in identifying technical solutions to resolve business problems in a rapidly changing, demanding and complex business environment.

Support more than one application and able to multi task between priorities.

Technologies:

- C#, .Net, .Net Core Angular, Java, Spring Boot, PL/SQL.
- JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

TELEFONICA

Direct Support Professional (2017/09-2020/11)

3 Years 1 Month

Functions and Achievements

Development of applications and web services for sales operation on support systems and massive processes for file storage.

Technologies:

- C#, .Net, .Net Core, Angular, Java, PL/SQL,
- JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

IRON MOUNTAIN

Development Analyst (2017/04 – 2017/08) 4 Months

Functions and Achievements

Gather and elicit requirements from clients to support and maintain web portal. Appraise and estimate new requirements and work in continuous effort to automate all data inputs for massive queries on company's web services, implementation of processes for the operational area, construction of scripts based on PL/SQL for analysis.

Technologies:

- Java, Web Services, Struts, PL/SQL.
- HTML, CSS

SII GROUP

Development Senior Analyst (2016/10 – 2017/04) 5 Months

Functions and Achievements

Raising policies for extracts generation in Porvenir company based on stored procedures made in Oracle 11g databases, JSF module design on Primefaces for extracts generation, construction of scripts based on PL/SQL for analysis.

Technologies:

PL/SQL.

STEFANINI COLOMBIA

Junior Developer (2015/11 – 2016/10) 11 Months

Functions and Achievements

Support and maintain a commission & revenue assurance system used across several countries such as: Chad, Ghana, Rwanda, Senegal, and Tanzania in Africa and Honduras, Salvador and Colombia in Latin America.

Technologies:

PL/SQL.

HITSS COLOMBIA SAS

Junior Developer (2014/04 – 2015/11) 1 Year 7 Months

Functions and Achievements

Development of shells for massive queries in HLR, construction of scripts based on PL/SQL for analysis.

Technologies:

PL/SQL.

VENTAS Y SERVICIOS S.A

Contact Center Analyst (2012/12 – 2013/06) 1 Year 7 months

Functions and Achievements

Java application development for management recordings on Contact Center platform, ease of use of the platform, implementation of web application for simultaneous incoming calls.

Technologies:

- Java, Primefaces, PL/SQL.
- HTML, CSS

COLTANQUES SAS

Direct Support Professional (2010/03 – 2012/12) 2 Years 9 Months

Functions and Achievements

Support to end users on applications in .Net programming language, solution of incidents on SQL Server. Excellent results in each of the assigned tasks. Responsibility, efficiency, punctuality and very good relations with co-workers and superiors.

Technologies:

• Visual Basic, T-SQL.

PERSONAL REFERENCES

Hernan Bernal

Scotiabank

Telephone Number: 3012886418

Neydi Paola Cristancho

Hitss Colombia SAS

Telephone Number: 3108029054

FAMILY REFERENCES

Martha Moreno Coltanques SAS

Telephone Number: 4222333

Daniela Reyes

Telephone Number: 3005595114

JULIAN CAMILO SANCHEZ DIAZ

ld. 1026258687